<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rasagy Sharma | Information Designer, Data Artist, Design Educator &amp; Sketchnoter</title>
    <link>http://rasagy.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rasagy Sharma | Information Designer, Data Artist, Design Educator &amp; Sketchnoter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 17:13:13 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://rasagy.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Disability and Digital Self Determination Workshop</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/swissnex-2023-disability-and-digital-self-determination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 17:13:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/swissnex-2023-disability-and-digital-self-determination/</guid>
      <description>Sketchnotes from the workshop at Swissnex on Disability &amp;amp; Self-Determination by Point of View &amp;amp; Design Beku.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tale of Datta — AI-generated comic on mythology of data</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/projects/datta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/projects/datta/</guid>
      <description>A comic about mythology of data, created with AI tools by Rasagy Sharma</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Rasagy Sharma</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 05:04:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/about/</guid>
      <description>Rasagy is an Information Designer, Data Artist, Design Educator &amp;amp; Compulsive Sketchnoter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Viz, the UnEmpathetic Art</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/outlier-2021-unempathetic-art-mushon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 15:20:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/outlier-2021-unempathetic-art-mushon/</guid>
      <description>Sketchnote of Outlier talk on Data Viz, the UnEmpathetic Art Mushon Zer-Aviv spoke at Outlier about how data viz is an un-empathetic art.
This was clearly one of the most thought-provoking talk, in which he questioned the role of data viz in building empathy, and the moral implications of this approach.
His talk was filled with amazing quotes, references &amp;amp; prompts to reflect upon.
“If I look at the mass, I will never act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telling Stories With Data and Music</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/outlier-2021-data-sonification-loud-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 14:40:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/outlier-2021-data-sonification-loud-numbers/</guid>
      <description>Sketchnote of Outlier talk on Data Sonification Duncan Geere &amp;amp; Miriam Quick spoke at Outlier about Data Sonification.
I was really looking forward to this talk, and getting a glimpse of their data sonification project — Loud Numbers. Since I had not experienced many sonification projects, I was fairly skeptical of it being a useful medium to communicate data.
Their talk was not just an excellent introduction to inspiring data sonification projects, they also had some great pointers on which audio parameter to use when (possible ontology/framework opportunity!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DxD: Data through Design exhibition</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/outlier-2021-dxd-sara/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 22:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/outlier-2021-dxd-sara/</guid>
      <description> Sketchnote of Outlier talk on Data through Design exhibition Sara Eichner introduced this year’s DataXDesign exhibition at Outlier.
I’ve always been intrigued by how the traditional art world looks at Data Art — her thoughts on curation, engagement &amp;amp; insightfulness were great!
The highlight was Brian Foo’s data sonification project called Two Trains that visualized income inequality on NYC Subway through three boroughs.
You can watch a video of the talk on Youtube: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do We Translate Cultural Experiences Into Data Stories?</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/outlier-2021-kontinentalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 15:40:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/outlier-2021-kontinentalist/</guid>
      <description>Sketchnote of talk about Kontinentalist Mick Yang &amp;amp; Isabella Chua spoke at Outlier about the amazing work by Kontinentalist team.
This was my favorite talk from Day #1. They showcased a series of inspiring &amp;amp; unique data stories based on their cultural experiences. From Rohingya refugees to chillis &amp;amp; queues in Asia — so many interesting topics!
What I loved was their process of creating these beautiful data stories:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Wisdom Map — Repository of life lessons &amp; insights</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/projects/world-wisdom-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 23:59:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/projects/world-wisdom-map/</guid>
      <description>What would a map of wisdom from all around the world look like? Result of an inspiring collaboration with Project Fuel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Workshop on Influencing Information</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/community/teaching-schematic-mapping-nid-paldi-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 20:20:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/community/teaching-schematic-mapping-nid-paldi-2020/</guid>
      <description>I was invited to conduct a two-week virtual Design Workshop at National Institute of Design, Ahmedabad for B.Des. 7th sem students.
My workshop focused on an introduction to Data Visualization, Visual Encoding, Data Storytelling &amp;amp; Cartography.
Hometown Schematic Map One of the exercises done in the workshop was to create a schematic map of their hometown, focused on a particular audience &amp;amp; purpose for this map. Some of the selected maps are shared below with their process, and the complete discussion &amp;amp; references are available on this Github issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar — What stories can you narrate with data?</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/community/webinar-data-storytelling-mit-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 16:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/community/webinar-data-storytelling-mit-id/</guid>
      <description>I got invited to conduct a virtual, interactive workshop on data storytelling, for MIT ID Innovation Program’s Virtual GradShow.
In the workshop, I explained why data needs to be narrated as stories, showed some case studies by Gramener &amp;amp; walked through the process of going from data analysis to narrating a story. I also focused on how design thinking’s user-centricity &amp;amp; encoding principles based on visual perception enable us to visualize insights that are useful &amp;amp; engaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fireside chat — Sketching &amp; Data Visualization</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/community/fireside-chat-sketching-dataviz-datavizsociety/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 01:02:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/community/fireside-chat-sketching-dataviz-datavizsociety/</guid>
      <description>I got a chance to join two incredible designers — Katherine Haugh &amp;amp; Duncan Geere — for a fireside chat on Sketching &amp;amp; Data Visualization. This chat was done virtually, moderated by Amy Cesal for the DataVizSociety.
We spoke about using sketching in the data viz process, using sketching as an aesthetic for data viz, and using sketchnoting as a way to visually represent information.
You can watch the session on Youtube:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar — Maps love Data: A voyage across the world of geo-visualization</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/community/webinar-maps-data-visualization-spa-bhopal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 15:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/community/webinar-maps-data-visualization-spa-bhopal/</guid>
      <description>I was invited to speak to the M.Des. students in Department of Design at SPA Bhopal as part of their Design Samvãd series of guest lectures.
I spoke about how maps are inherently a form of data visualization, and how they enable a variety of geo-visualizations.
Slides from my talk are available on SpeakerDeck:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loopimation — Creating looping animations in P5.js</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/community/workshop-loopimation-pcd-blr-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 14:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/community/workshop-loopimation-pcd-blr-2020/</guid>
      <description>Loopimation was a short workshop on building looping geometric animations in P5.js that I conducted at Processing Community Day 2020 in Bengaluru (India).
Talking about historical techniques for animations You can explore some of the example starter P5.js sketches, using the wonderful p5.createLoop library.
An example looping animation created in workshop Slides are available on Google Slides:
You can also download &amp;amp; print my storyboarding template for planning your animations. More details on the Github repository for the workshop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geo Visualization &amp; Digital Cartography</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/community/teaching-geoviz-digital-cartography-nid-blr-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 19:12:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/community/teaching-geoviz-digital-cartography-nid-blr-2019/</guid>
      <description>I was invited back at my alma mater to teach M.Des. Information Design students for their Geo Visualization &amp;amp; Digital Cartography module, led by Prof. Chakradhar Saswade. My sessions focused on an introduction to Cartography, types of Geo Visualization, Schematic Mapping, Sensory Mapping &amp;amp; Choropleths in Excel!
Hometown Schematic Map One of the exercises was to create a schematic map of their hometown, focused on a particular audience &amp;amp; purpose for this map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Interaction Design Day (IxDD)</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/community/volunteering-ixdd-ibm-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/community/volunteering-ixdd-ibm-2019/</guid>
      <description>I helped organize the World Interaction Design Day 2019 celebrations at IBM, Bangalore. As one of the local leader for IxDA, I was involved in speaker curation &amp;amp; logistics for the event.
Teams collaborating during the Ethics Sprint workshop at IxDD 2019 Speaker lineup We had two talks &amp;amp; one workshop exploring Trust &amp;amp; Responsibility from the lens of Interaction Design:
Vinay Kesari spoke on Data Protection Law in India. Sundhindra V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>data.n.coded — collection of creative coding experiments</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/projects/data-n-coded/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 01:02:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/projects/data-n-coded/</guid>
      <description>Home for my experiments with generative &amp;amp; data art in P5.js</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing 500 Days of Summer</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/blog/visualizing-500-days-of-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 23:22:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/blog/visualizing-500-days-of-summer/</guid>
      <description>This semester began with a module on Narratives, and when I got a chance to pick a topic for my Information Visualization module, I just had to visualize this movie’s non-linear narrative!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing 500 Days of Summer</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/projects/500days/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 05:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/projects/500days/</guid>
      <description>Visualization of the non-linear narrative of the movie: 500 Days of Summer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections from my first year at design school</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/blog/my-first-year-at-design-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 18:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/blog/my-first-year-at-design-school/</guid>
      <description>Exactly one year back, I decided to leave my job as a UX Designer and joined National Institute of Design, Bangalore to pursue Post Grad in Information &amp;amp; Interface Design. A year later, I felt it would be a good time to reflect on a few things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Alberto Cairo’s MOOC on Infographics &amp; Data Visualization</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/blog/week-1-alberto-cairos-mooc-on-infographics-data-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 04:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/blog/week-1-alberto-cairos-mooc-on-infographics-data-visualization/</guid>
      <description>As an assignment, we had to pick one of the many infographics, critique it, &amp;amp; suggest alternatives to the infographic. Here&amp;rsquo;s my critique &amp;amp; some sketches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s not a font, it’s a typeface!</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/blog/its-not-a-font-its-a-typeface/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2012 15:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/blog/its-not-a-font-its-a-typeface/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite ways to bug everyone, is to scream this whenever someone mixes the terms &lt;em&gt;font&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;typeface&lt;/em&gt;. So here&amp;rsquo;s a poster on it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing T.T. Finals at NID Bangalore</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/blog/visualizing-table-tennis-finals-at-nid-bangalore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 12:12:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/blog/visualizing-table-tennis-finals-at-nid-bangalore/</guid>
      <description>Last month, the (newly elected) sports committee of NID Bangalore organized a Table Tennis Tournament. Here’s my first attempt at making a data visualization – Final matches between Amal &amp;amp; Upamanyu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Flag in CSS3 – Republic Day Special!</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/blog/indian-flag-in-css3-republic-day-india-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 13:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/blog/indian-flag-in-css3-republic-day-india-special/</guid>
      <description>Making anything &amp;amp; everything in CSS3 seems to be the rage these days. So to celebrate the Republic Day of India, I decided to make the Flag of India in CSS3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humanize the Android</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/droidcon-india-2011-humanize-the-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 18:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/droidcon-india-2011-humanize-the-android/</guid>
      <description>Last month I volunteered for organizing Droidcon India at Bangalore &amp;amp; I squeezed some time to sketchnote for the session – “Humanize the Android” by Vivek Juneja.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Accessibility and HTML5 Boilerplate</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/geekup-2011-web-accessibility-and-html5-boilerplate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 01:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/geekup-2011-web-accessibility-and-html5-boilerplate/</guid>
      <description>In October, I attended a Geekup session on Web Accessibility &amp;amp; HTML5 Boilerplate by HasGeek. Here are the 2 Sketchnotes I made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas and a Happy New Blog!</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/blog/merry-christmas-and-a-happy-new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/blog/merry-christmas-and-a-happy-new-blog/</guid>
      <description>What better time to start a new blog, than NOW? Finally, I have one place to archive my thoughts, ideas &amp;amp; sketchnotes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Chef Run — My game for CodeChef Contest</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/blog/run-chef-run-codechef-contest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 13:31:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/blog/run-chef-run-codechef-contest/</guid>
      <description>My entry for CodeChef contest: A game made in Flash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketch — Goodbye Seniors!</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/blog/sketch-goodbye-seniors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2008 04:04:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/blog/sketch-goodbye-seniors/</guid>
      <description>A quick caricature of two of my favorite seniors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketch — Thank You, Adil Sir!</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/blog/sketch-thank-you-adil-sir/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/blog/sketch-thank-you-adil-sir/</guid>
      <description>A small sketch for a prof who introduced me to design!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell, BITS Goa batch of 2005!</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/blog/bits-goa-farewell-2005-batch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 20:08:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/blog/bits-goa-farewell-2005-batch/</guid>
      <description>A short note to some of the amazing seniors from 2005 batch that I’ll miss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Creation</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/blog/blog-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2008 11:04:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/blog/blog-creation/</guid>
      <description>My first post on my first personal blog!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
