<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community Building on Rasagy Sharma | Information Designer, Data Artist, Sketchnoter</title>
    <link>http://rasagy.in/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community Building on Rasagy Sharma | Information Designer, Data Artist, Sketchnoter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 20:20:20 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://rasagy.in/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Design Workshop on Influencing Information</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/community/teaching-schematic-mapping-nid-paldi-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 20:20:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/community/teaching-schematic-mapping-nid-paldi-2020/</guid>
      <description>I was invited to conduct a two-week virtual Design Workshop at National Institute of Design, Ahmedabad for B.Des. 7th sem students.
My workshop focused on an introduction to Data Visualization, Visual Encoding, Data Storytelling &amp;amp; Cartography.
Hometown Schematic Map One of the exercises done in the workshop was to create a schematic map of their hometown, focused on a particular audience &amp;amp; purpose for this map. Some of the selected maps are shared below with their process, and the complete discussion &amp;amp; references are available on this Github issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar — What stories can you narrate with data?</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/community/webinar-data-storytelling-mit-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 16:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/community/webinar-data-storytelling-mit-id/</guid>
      <description>I got invited to conduct a virtual, interactive workshop on data storytelling, for MIT ID Innovation Program’s Virtual GradShow.
In the workshop, I explained why data needs to be narrated as stories, showed some case studies by Gramener &amp;amp; walked through the process of going from data analysis to narrating a story. I also focused on how design thinking’s user-centricity &amp;amp; encoding principles based on visual perception enable us to visualize insights that are useful &amp;amp; engaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fireside chat — Sketching &amp; Data Visualization</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/community/fireside-chat-sketching-dataviz-datavizsociety/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 01:02:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/community/fireside-chat-sketching-dataviz-datavizsociety/</guid>
      <description>I got a chance to join two incredible designers — Katherine Haugh &amp;amp; Duncan Geere — for a fireside chat on Sketching &amp;amp; Data Visualization. This chat was done virtually, moderated by Amy Cesal for the DataVizSociety.
We spoke about using sketching in the data viz process, using sketching as an aesthetic for data viz, and using sketchnoting as a way to visually represent information.
You can watch the session on Youtube:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar — Maps love Data: A voyage across the world of geo-visualization</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/community/webinar-maps-data-visualization-spa-bhopal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 15:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/community/webinar-maps-data-visualization-spa-bhopal/</guid>
      <description>I was invited to speak to the M.Des. students in Department of Design at SPA Bhopal as part of their Design Samvãd series of guest lectures.
I spoke about how maps are inherently a form of data visualization, and how they enable a variety of geo-visualizations.
 Slides from my talk are available on SpeakerDeck:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loopimation — Creating looping animations in P5.js</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/community/workshop-loopimation-pcd-blr-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 14:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/community/workshop-loopimation-pcd-blr-2020/</guid>
      <description>Loopimation was a short workshop on building looping geometric animations in P5.js that I conducted at Processing Community Day 2020 in Bengaluru (India).
Talking about historical techniques for animations   You can explore some of the example starter P5.js sketches, using the wonderful p5.createLoop library.
An example looping animation created in workshop   Slides are available on Google Slides:
 You can also download &amp;amp; print my storyboarding template for planning your animations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geo Visualization &amp; Digital Cartography</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/community/teaching-geoviz-digital-cartography-nid-blr-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 19:12:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/community/teaching-geoviz-digital-cartography-nid-blr-2019/</guid>
      <description>I was invited back at my alma mater to teach M.Des. Information Design students for their Geo Visualization &amp;amp; Digital Cartography module, led by Prof. Chakradhar Saswade. My sessions focused on an introduction to Cartography, types of Geo Visualization, Schematic Mapping, Sensory Mapping &amp;amp; Choropleths in Excel!
Hometown Schematic Map One of the exercises was to create a schematic map of their hometown, focused on a particular audience &amp;amp; purpose for this map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Interaction Design Day (IxDD)</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/community/volunteering-ixdd-ibm-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/community/volunteering-ixdd-ibm-2019/</guid>
      <description>I helped organize the World Interaction Design Day 2019 celebrations at IBM, Bangalore. As one of the local leader for IxDA, I was involved in speaker curation &amp;amp; logistics for the event.
Teams collaborating during the Ethics Sprint workshop at IxDD 2019   Speaker lineup We had two talks &amp;amp; one workshop exploring Trust &amp;amp; Responsibility from the lens of Interaction Design:
 Vinay Kesari spoke on Data Protection Law in India.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
