<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sketchnotes on Rasagy Sharma | Information Designer, Data Artist, Sketchnoter</title>
    <link>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sketchnotes on Rasagy Sharma | Information Designer, Data Artist, Sketchnoter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 15:20:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data Viz, the UnEmpathetic Art</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/outlier-2021-unempathetic-art-mushon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 15:20:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/outlier-2021-unempathetic-art-mushon/</guid>
      <description>Sketchnote of Outlier talk on Data Viz, the UnEmpathetic Art   Mushon Zer-Aviv spoke at Outlier about how data viz is an un-empathetic art.
This was clearly one of the most thought-provoking talk, in which he questioned the role of data viz in building empathy, and the moral implications of this approach.
His talk was filled with amazing quotes, references &amp;amp; prompts to reflect upon.
 “If I look at the mass, I will never act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telling Stories With Data and Music</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/outlier-2021-data-sonification-loud-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 14:40:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/outlier-2021-data-sonification-loud-numbers/</guid>
      <description>Sketchnote of Outlier talk on Data Sonification   Duncan Geere &amp;amp; Miriam Quick spoke at Outlier about Data Sonification.
I was really looking forward to this talk, and getting a glimpse of their data sonification project — Loud Numbers . Since I had not experienced many sonification projects, I was fairly skeptical of it being a useful medium to communicate data.
Their talk was not just an excellent introduction to inspiring data sonification projects, they also had some great pointers on which audio parameter to use when (possible ontology/framework opportunity!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DxD: Data through Design exhibition</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/outlier-2021-dxd-sara/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 22:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/outlier-2021-dxd-sara/</guid>
      <description> Sketchnote of Outlier talk on Data through Design exhibition   Sara Eichner introduced this year’s DataXDesign exhibition at Outlier.
I’ve always been intrigued by how the traditional art world looks at Data Art — her thoughts on curation, engagement &amp;amp; insightfulness were great!
The highlight was Brian Foo’s data sonification project called Two Trains that visualized income inequality on NYC Subway through three boroughs.
You can watch a video of the talk on Youtube :   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do We Translate Cultural Experiences Into Data Stories?</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/outlier-2021-kontinentalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 15:40:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/outlier-2021-kontinentalist/</guid>
      <description>Sketchnote of talk about Kontinentalist   Mick Yang &amp;amp; Isabella Chua spoke at Outlier about the amazing work by Kontinentalist team.
This was my favorite talk from Day #1. They showcased a series of inspiring &amp;amp; unique data stories based on their cultural experiences. From Rohingya refugees to chillis &amp;amp; queues in Asia — so many interesting topics!
What I loved was their process of creating these beautiful data stories:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humanize the Android</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/droidcon-india-2011-humanize-the-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 18:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/droidcon-india-2011-humanize-the-android/</guid>
      <description>Last month I volunteered for organizing Droidcon India at Bangalore &amp;amp; I squeezed some time to sketchnote for the session – “Humanize the Android” by Vivek Juneja.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Accessibility and HTML5 Boilerplate</title>
      <link>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/geekup-2011-web-accessibility-and-html5-boilerplate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 01:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rasagy.in/sketchnotes/geekup-2011-web-accessibility-and-html5-boilerplate/</guid>
      <description>In October, I attended a Geekup session on Web Accessibility &amp;amp; HTML5 Boilerplate by HasGeek. Here are the 2 Sketchnotes I made.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
